Guide to the George Bird Grinnell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, Subject Files, and Other Papers, 1859-1939; Series II; 6.5 linear feet (17 boxes)
  - Subject files
    - Alaska game bill: printed material, 1903-1918 (Box 30, Folder 141, Reel 40U)
    - American Big Game In Its Haunts, 1905 (Box 30, Folder 142, Reel 40U)
    - Antelope, 1895-1916, 1919-1930, undated (Box 31, Folder 143-144, Reel 40U)
    - Audubon family; Audubon Society, 1908-1939, undated (Box 31, Folder 145, Reel 40U)
    - Bear-Wolverine-Wolf-Coyote, 1898, 1913- 1930, undated (Box 31, Folder 146, Reel 40U)
    - Bent family; Bent's Old Fort, 1909-1929 (Box 31, Folder 147, Reel 41U)
      See also: box 30, folder 130
    - Birds, 1869-1896 (Box 31, Folder 148, Reel 41U)
      See also: box 42, folders 227-229
    - Birds, 1909-1938, undated (Box 31, Folder 149, Reel 41U)
    - Book collecting, 1912-1929, undated (Box 31, Folder 150, Reel 41U)
    - Boone and Crockett Club, 1901-1931 (Box 31, Folder 151, Reel 41U)
      See also: box 26, folder 59
      See also: box 27, folder 81
      See also: box 30, folder 137
      See also: box 35, folder 195
    - Boone and Crockett Club, undated (Box 31, Folder 152, Reel 41U)
    - Buffalo, 1888-1929 (Box 32, Folder 153, Reel 41U)
    - Buffalo, undated (Box 32, Folder 154, Reel 41U)
    - Caribou, 1899-1900, 1915-1923, undated (Box 32, Folder 155, Reel 41U)
    - Coyote
      See: box 31, folder 146
    - Deer
      See: box 32, folders 156-158
      See: box 34, folder 179
    - Elk, 1859-1915, 1917-1925, 1927-1928, undated (Box 32, Folder 156-158, Reel 41U)
    - Forest and Stream, 1876, 1903-1930 (Box 32, Folder 159-160, Reel 42U)
    - Forestry legislation, 1893-1910, 1920-1921, undated (Box 32, Folder 161, Reel 42U)
    - Fraser, George C.: notes on a journey taken with George Bird Grinnell through western New Mexico, eastern Arizona, and southwestern Colorado, 1920 (Box 33, Folder 162, Reel 42U)
    - Furbearers, 1910-1927 (Box 33, Folder 163, Reel 42U)
    - Fur seals, 1884-1913, undated (Box 33, Folder 164, Reel 42U)
    - Game, 1921-1929, undated (Box 33, Folder 165, Reel 42U)
    - Glacier National Park, 1905-1932, undated (Box 33, Folder 166-171, Reel 42U)
    - Goat, 1887-1891, 1918-1929, undated (Box 33, Folder 172-173, Reel 42U)
    - Indians, 1894-1910 (Box 34, Folder 174, Reel 43U)
      See also: box 35, folder 196
    - Indians, 1911-1914 (Box 34, Folder 175, Reel 43U)
    - Indians, 1915-1917 (Box 34, Folder 176, Reel 43U)
      See also: box 35, folders 196-197
    - Indians, 1918-1921 (Box 34, Folder 177, Reel 43U)
      See also: box 35, folder 197
    - Indians, 1922-1930, undated (Box 34, Folder 178, Reel 43U)
      Related Materials
      See also: box 35, folders 197-198
    - Kaibab deer, 1923-1926, undated (Box 34, Folder 179, Reel 43U)
    - Kipp, Joe, 1885-1922 (Box 34, Folder 180, Reel 43U)
    - Marsh expedition, 1876-1877 (Box 34, Folder 181, Reel 43U)
    - Marsh Island, 1912-1913, 1919-1924, undated (Box 34, Folder 182-183, Reel 43U)
    - Migratory bird legislation, 1907-1926 (Box 34, Folder 184-185, Reel 43U)
    - Migratory bird legislation, 1927-1932, undated (Box 35, Folder 186, Reel 43U)
    - Moose, 1874, 1876, 1893, 1901, 1916, undated (Box 35, Folder 187, Reel 43U)
    - Mt. McKinley National Park, 1916-1921 (Box 35, Folder 188, Reel 44U)
    - National parks, 1921-1929, undated (Box 35, Folder 189, Reel 44U)
    - Parks, 1921, 1927 (Box 35, Folder 190, Reel 44U)
    - Pawnee Hero Stories and Folk Tales, 1889-1890 (Box 35, Folder 191, Reel 44U)
    - Publications by Grinnell, requests for and comments on, 1889-1930 (Box 35, Folder 192, Reel 44U)
    - Sheep, 1873-1901, 1911-1928, undated (Box 35, Folder 193-194, Reel 44U)
    - Sheldon, Charles, 1926-1934 (Box 35, Folder 195, Reel 44U)
      See also: box 31, folder 151
      See also: box 32, folder 158
    - West, 1890, 1902-1929, undated (Box 35, Folder 196-198, Reel 44U)
    - Wildfowl, 1901-1930, undated (Box 36, Folder 199-200, Reel 44U)
    - Wolf
    - Wolverine
    - Wood, William, 1911, 1921-1922, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 201, Reel 45U)
    - Woodcock, 1919-1926, undated (Box 36, Folder 202, Reel 45U)
    - Yale University, 1868-1935 (Box 36, Folder 203, Reel 45U)
    - Yellowstone National Park, 1901-1919 (Box 36, Folder 204, Reel 45U)
      See also: box 25, folder 50
      See also: box 30, folder 131
    - Yellowstone National Park, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 205, Reel 45U)
    - Yellowstone National Park, 1921-1929, undated (Box 36, Folder 206, Reel 45U)
  - Other papers
    - Accounts, 1922-1926 (Box 36, Folder 207, Reel 45U)
    - Bibliography, books, 1930, 1933, undated (Box 36, Folder 208, Reel 45U)
    - Bibliography, Forest and Stream, undated (Box 36, Folder 209, Reel 45U)
    - Biographical data, undated (Box 36, Folder 210, Reel 45U)
    - Certificates, 1906-1928, undated (Box 36, Folder 211, Reel 45U)
    - Clippings about George Bird Grinnell, 1889-1894, 1903-1930 undated (Box 36, Folder 212-213, Reel 45U)
    - Index cards, undated (Box 37, Reel 46U)
    - Index cards, undated (Box 38, Reel 46U)
    - Memoirs, 1915 (Box 39, Folder 214-215, Reel 46U)
    - Notebooks, 1888, 1920, 1922, undated (Box 39, Folder 216-219, Reel 46U)
    - Notes, undated (Box 39, Folder 220, Reel 46U)
    - Photographs, 1916-1921, undated (Box 39, Folder 221, Reel 46U)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 40, Reel 46U)
      See also: box 30, folder 136
      See also: box 31, folders 151-154
      See also: box 33, folders 171
      See also: box 33, folders 173-178
      See also: box 34, folder 181
      See also: box 34, folder 185
      See also: box 36, folders 199-200
      See also: box 36, folder 202
      See also: box 36, folders 204-206
    - Poems and songs, 1925, 1930, undated (Box 41, Folder 222, Reel 46U)
    - Writings: drafts, 1928, undated (Box 41, Folder 223, Reel 46U)
      See also: box 29, folder 113
      See also: box 31, folders 143-147
      See also: box 32, folders 153-158
      See also: box 33, folders 170-171
      See also: box 34, folders 181-183
      See also: box 35, folders 193-195
      See also: box 35, folders 198-200
    - Writings: drafts, undated (Box 41, Folder 224-225, Reel 46U)
    - Writings: printed copies, 1876-1929 (Box 41, Folder 226, Reel 46U)
- Additional Material, 1870-1875; Accession 1991-M-050; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Diane Kaplan 1991 Jan
  Received from: Connecticut Audubon Society, 1991 January 2
  - Birds: collection catalogue of George Bird and Morton Grinnell, with unidentified financial records, Circa 1871-1875 (Box 42, Folder 227, Reel 47U)
  - Birds: "Manuscript Book" of George Bird and Morton Grinnell, 1870 (Box 42, Folder 228, Reel 47U)
  - Birds: ["Manuscript Book": draft], Circa 1870 (Box 42, Folder 229, Reel 47U)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-033
  - "On the Osteology of Geococcyx Californianus, Bd." [handwritten draft of George Bird Grinnell's Ph.D. dissertation, Yale University], [1880?] (Box 1)